Guide to the Samuel Halperin Puck and Judge cartoon collection, 1879-1903 MS2121
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Illustrations from "Puck", 1879-1903; MS2121 Series 1; 2 Linear feet
  - The Political Handicap - Who Will Ride the Demcratic Entry?, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 6)
  - Legalized Plunderers, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 7)
  - This is not the New York Stock Exchange. It is the patronage exchanged called U.S. Senate, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 8)
  - Our Precious Plumber, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 9)
  - Our Costly Funerals, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 10)
  - The Surrogate's Court, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 11)
  - Our Indian Policy -A House of Cards, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 12)
  - Political Cannibalism, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 13)
    Text on document "The Democratic Party of the South intends to maintain itself at the Expense of the Democratic Party of the North."
  - Utah Defies - the Mormon Commander Mustering His Forces, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 14)
  - Foes in his path. - The Herculean task before our next president., undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 15)
  - Puck cover illustrations [multiple issues], Circa 1879-1893; MS2121 Series 1 (Flat box 16, Folder 5)
  - Puck cartoons [multiple issues], Circa 1880-1890, undated; MS2121 Series 1 (Flat box 16, Folder 6)
  - Puck illustrations double-page lithographs [multiple issues], Circa 1980s-1890s; MS2121 Series 1 (Flat box 17, Folder 1)
    Transfer from Luther Brady Art Gallery June 27, 2022 (Accession 2022.030)
- Illustrations from "Judge", 1887-1900; MS2121 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains illustrations for the magazine "Judge" for the years 1887-1900. Undated illustrations are also included.
  - "Democracy's Dilemma.", 04/02/1887 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "The Reputable Citizen and the Bad Spirit.", 04/09/1887 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "The Siamese Twins.", 04/16/1887 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "An Appeal to a Country Without a Soul Above.", 04/30/1887 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "The Second Term Question.", 05/07/1887 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "The Political Umpire.-His Lot is Not a Happy One.", 05/21/1887 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Giving Them a Chance.", 06/04/1887 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "The New Combine." (2 copies), 06/11/1887 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Tough on Micawber,", 06/25/1887 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "The Weakening of the Props.", 07/02/1887 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "The Three R's.", 07/09/1887 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "The Sharp and the Flat.", 07/16/1887 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Excommunicated.", 07/23/1887 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "The Disgusted Musicians.", 07/30/1887 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "Brute and Dog.", 08/06/1887 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "The Cleveland Puzzle.", 08/13/1887 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "Too Many Guides.", 08/20/1887 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - "A Sickener for Dave!", 09/10/1887 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - "Our Society and the Peer.", 09/17/1887 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Questioning the Sphynx.", 10/01/1887 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - "Under Two Flags.", 10/29/1887 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "King John Bull and the Democratic Pie.", 03/17/1888 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - "Hands Off!", 08/04/1888 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - "The Goose That Lays the Golden Eggs.", 09/08/1888 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - "The Democratic "TRUST.", 09/29/1888 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - "Two Sides to a Hypocrite.", 10/13/1888 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - "Free Trade England Wants the Earth.", 10/27/1888 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - "The Stars and Stripes Are Good Enough for U.S.", 11/17/1888 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - "The Panama Canal-The Lion in the Path.", 01/26/1889 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - "The Presidential Prestidigitateur.", 02/02/1889 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - "A Friendly Admonition.", 02/09/1889 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - "The Straws That Break the Camel's Back.", 04/06/1889 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - "The Great Judicial Ring.", 10/19/1889 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - "American Aristocracy.", 06/17/1893 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - "A Natural Mistake.", 06/24/1893 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - "Congressman Holman-"I OBJECT!"", 07/01/1893 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - "The Three Balls.", 08/12/1893 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - "WHOA!", 09/02/1893 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - "The Right Kind of Relief.", 09/09/1893 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - "We Are Safe.", 05/12/1900 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - "That Little Word "IF.", 05/26/1900 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - "Administration Soda.", undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - "An August Medley.", undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - "Back at Him."/ "A Safety-Raiser."/ "A Happy Conclusion."/ "A Youthful Pessimist."/ "An Unfailing Sign.", undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - "Back From the Adirondacks.", undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - "Beer and Music.", undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - "Before Taking..... After Taking.", undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - "Begorra! It Was."/ "No Use.", undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - "The Career of the Stage-Struck Society Beauty.", undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - "A Country Officials Visit to the City.", undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - "The "Deadly Parallel.", undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - "A Disastrous Error.", undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - "Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde.", undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - "The Drill at Washington.", undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - "Easter Egglets.", undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - "The First of May.", undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - "Getting Out of a Difficulty.", undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - "Great Scott! What Struck Us?", undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - "His Wife's Revenge.", undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - "It Is Political Death to Let Go.", undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - "It Makes Them Dreadfully Sick.", undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - "It Was a Struggle of the Midgets.", undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - "The Jealous Rival, the Golf-Ball, and the Bad Egg.", undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - "Left!", undated (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - "Letters to the Editor.", undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - "Making it Hot for the Old Democratic Party." (2 copies), undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - "The "Man of Destiny" Overshadows the Fathers of His Country.", undated (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - "Mr. Sullivan's Visit to President Cleveland.", undated (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - "A Nice Young Man and His Sporty New Hat.", undated (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - "The Noisy Boy in the European Lodging-House.", undated (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - "Passing it Along; Or, Why the Janitor Mended the Roof.", undated (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - "Ranching in the Wild West-As it is.", undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - "The Reason of It.", undated (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - "The Rival Transatlantic Streams.", undated (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - "The Rope as a Hotel Fire-escape.", undated (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - "A Scheme of Necessity.", undated (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - "Sea-Side Sport." (2 copies), undated (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - "Seaside Studies.", undated (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - "Social Protection.", undated (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - "Summer Comforts.", undated (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - "Summer Ideas.", undated (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - "Those New Canes.", undated (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - "Too "Free" to be Good.", undated (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - "A Week's Vacation.", undated (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - "Why the Emigrant Prefers New York to the Wild West.", undated (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - "The Three Disgraces", 04/23/1887 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "How Justice Slips Up. The same old Banana Peel!", 06/18/1887 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "The Old Coat.", 09/03/1887 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Full title of illustration: "The Old Coat. Chorus of Tailors-'Hadn't you better let us repair that coat? It's too old-fashioned for these go-ahead timies.' Uncle Sam-'The coat is good enough for me, and will last at least another hundred years!'"
  - "Questioning the Sphinx. Democratic Editors (frantically)-'Are you a candidate for President, or are you not? Answer!' ", 10/01/1887 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "He Killed The Goose That Laid The Golden Eggs. (Regular work and good wages.)", 08/19/1893 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "For Their Country's Good.", undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Full text on illustration: "For Their Country's Good. 'There is a very strong movement being made to transport our convicts to Alaska, and so populate that country, and thereby settle the Convict Labor Question.'-Daily Paper. Original Settlers.-'If they come in, why then we will go out.' "
  - "America's Heary Welcome To The Innocent Emigrant.", undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - For Their Country's Good, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Item 8)
    On cartoon:
    "There is a very strong movement being made to transport our convicts to Alaska, and so populate that country, and thereby settle the Convict Labor Question" Daily Press
    Original Settlers "If they come in, why then we will go out"
  - "Halt!", 1887 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Full text on illustration: "Halt! Spirit of The War For The Union.-'Had you gought for those flags, you would not be so quick to give them away!' Cleveleand.-'Great Scott! I thought you were dead and forgotten long ago. I only meant to please Mr. Solid South. They're rubbish anyhow.' "
  - "Bringing Free Trade To The Farmer's Door.", 1888 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Full text on illustration: "Bringing Free Trade To The Farmer's Door. The Mills Free Trade Bill includes Vegetables, Fruits, Potatoes, Hops, Flax, and Wool. American Farmers.-What shall we do? We cannot compete with European Cheap Labor. English Importer.-Go to Europe and Farm or Starve!"
  - "The Nations Favorite. In the Interest of Unity and Harmony, Judge makes a Nomination for 1888 on which all parties would unite." (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Big Blaines Little Enemies. The Democratic Editors resort to all kinds of disreputable means in their attempt to find a bad record for Mr. Blaine as Secretary of State.", 1889 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "The Last Scene in Uncle Grover's Cabin.-The Death Of Little Eva Democracy.", 1889 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Full text for illustration: "The Last Scene In Uncle Grover's Cabin.-The Death Of Little Eva Democracy. 'Put erside d' liddle playt'ings; Lay d' banjo on d' flo: Hush yo' voices down t' nuffin, Liddle Eva's got ter go. All them Doctors tried to pull her Frough d' sickness,-t'warn't no use Pills en braces, yarbs en mixtur's Jes' helped out ter cook her goose."
  - "Saints and Sinner-The Split In The Democratic Party.", 1889 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "On The Hog.", 1903 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "Free (Trade) Lunch.", undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Full text on illustration: "Free (Trade) Lunch. Grover Cleveland prposes to make Free Lunch of the American Workingman's Bread and Cheese, for the benefit of European Pauper Laborers."
  - "Foreign Tramps Warned Off!", undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Full text on illustration: "Foreign Tramps Warned Off! 'We have happily maintained a policy of avoiding all interference with European affairs. We have a just right to expect that our European policy will be the American policy of European courts. We have a clear right to expect that no European Government will seek to establish colonial dependencies upon the territory of Independent American States. That which a sense of justice restrains us from seeking they may be reasonably expected willingly to forego. We shall neither fail to respect the flag of any friendly nation or the just rights of its citizens, nor to exact the like treatment for our own.' President Harrison's Inauguration Address. Foreign Powers-'By Jingo! another Party has the Place!' "
  - "Cleveland, The English Clothier.", undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Full text on illustration: "Cleveland, The English Clotheir. Uncle Sam-'This style may do for John Bull, but it doesn't suit me. Ill stick to my old clothes.' Chorus of Anglo-Maniacs - 'Oh! it looks chawming! And it's so English, you know!' "
  - "The Phantom Ship.", undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "Cain and Abel. The Two Altars to Liberty.", undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "Side-Tracked.", undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - John Bull Finds His Moses, undated; Series 2 (Flat box 15, Item 1)
    Text on document "John Bull - "Ah! This is the Moses that will open the American Land of Milk and Honey, to the products of my Pauper Labor!"
  - The Democratic Drug Store, undated; Series 2 (Flat box 15, Item 2)
    Text on document "Uncle Sam - "I'm not going to take that stuff - that Patent Medicine has been denounced and exposed by the whole American people. Hereafter I will get my prescriptions across the way."
  - Judge cover illustrations [multiple issues], 1886-1903; MS2121 Series 2 (Flat box 16, Folder 3)
  - Judge cartoons [multiple issues], Circa 1880-1903; MS2121 Series 2 (Flat box 16, Folder 4)
- Loose pages from Puck and Judge, Series 3; 3 Linear Feet 3 flat boxes
  This series contains loose pages from Puck and Judge magazine. There are a wealth of advertisements and cartoons from the late 1800s and early 1900s. Many of the advertisements are for medicine and other medical treatments. Sometimes the loose pages are the center image from the magazine which is often a larger color political cartoon. Unfortunately, there is no order to these materials.
  Gift of Samuel Halperin, March 2009 (2009.28)
  - Loose pages from Puck and Judge magazines, undated; Series 3 (Flat box 12, Folder 1)
  - Loose pages from Puck and Judge magazines, undated; Series 3 (Flat box 12, Folder 2)
  - Loose pages from Puck and Judge magazines, undated; Series 3 (Flat box 12, Folder 3)
  - Loose pages from Puck and Judge magazines, undated; Series 3 (Flat box 12, Folder 4)
  - Loose pages from Puck and Judge magazines, undated; Series 3 (Flat box 13, Folder 1)
  - Loose pages from Puck and Judge magazines, undated; Series 3 (Flat box 13, Folder 2)
  - Loose pages from Puck and Judge magazines, undated; Series 3 (Flat box 13, Folder 3)
  - Loose pages from Puck and Judge magazine, undated; Series 3 (Flat box 14, Folder 1)
  - Loose pages from Puck and Judge magazine, undated; Series 3 (Flat box 14, Folder 2)
  - Loose pages from Puck and Judge magazine, Undated; Series 3 (Flat box 14, Folder 3)